Guide to the Kilpatrick Collection of Cherokee Manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Notebook #16: "Doyanisi I, II"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1542)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Dan Scott Coll."
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1543)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1544)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "tlutlu ugasinuti Coll"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1545)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1546)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Gwana ditsiga [Peach Eater] Coll"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1547)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1548)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1549)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1550)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1551)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1552)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1553)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1554)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Wadi Coll Ned Christie b. 1896? Goback Christie b. 1898? Sam Christie (son of Goback)"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1555)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1556)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1557)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1558)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1559)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1560)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1561)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 18, Folder 1562)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Toyanisi I"
  - Medical formula, 1933 July 28 (Box 19, Folder 1563)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1564)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Birth and death dates, undated (Box 19, Folder 1565)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1566)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1567)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1568)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1569)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1570)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1571)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1572)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1573)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Letter in English, circa 1924 (Box 19, Folder 1574)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1575)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1576)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1577)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1578)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1579)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1580)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1581)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Bible citation, undated (Box 19, Folder 1582)
  - Recto: Community note; Verso: List of names, 1933 September 11 (Box 19, Folder 1583)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1584)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1585)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1586)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1587)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1588)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1589)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1590)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1591)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1592)
  - Recto: Note in English; Verso: Medical formula, 1934 October 31 (Box 19, Folder 1593)
  - Medical formula, 1933 July 28 (Box 19, Folder 1594)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1595)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1596)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1597)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1598)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1599)
  - Medical formula and list of numbers, 1911 (Box 19, Folder 1600)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1601)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1602)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1603)
  - Medical formula, 1931 August 7 (Box 19, Folder 1604)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1605)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1606)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1607)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1608)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1609)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1610)
  - Medical formula, 1929 July 11 (Box 19, Folder 1611)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1612)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1613)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1614)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1615)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1616)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1617)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Doyanisi III"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1618)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Doyanisi IV"
  - Medical formula, 1939 February 14 (Box 19, Folder 1619)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1620)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Family history, circa 1945 (Box 19, Folder 1621)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Doyanisi V"
  - Financial record, 1926 March 11 (Box 19, Folder 1622)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1623)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1624)
  - Medical formula, 1931 August 6 (Box 19, Folder 1625)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1626)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1627)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1628)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1629)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Adam Hendricks Coll."
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1630)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1631)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1632)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1633)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1634)
  - Folder with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Adelak'tiya Formula Book II", and with Envelope, undated (Box 19, Folder 1635)
    Folder for a medical formula notebook, no notebook included
  - Folder with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Unidentified Formula Book I", undated (Box 19, Folder 1636)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Egi Collection obtained July 1962" Folder for medical formula notebook, no notebook included
  - Folder with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Dlanus Tôyanis' Formula Book IV", undated (Box 19, Folder 1637)
    Folder for medical formula notebook, no notebook included
  - Folder with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Ahwigadoga-Dil'tidegi Formula Book", undated (Box 19, Folder 1638)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1639)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1640)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1641)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1642)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1643)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1644)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1645)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1646)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1647)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 19, Folder 1648)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1649)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1650)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1651)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1652)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1653)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1654)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1655)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1656)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1657)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1658)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1659)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1660)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 1661)
- Notebook #19
  - Kilpatrick notebook cover, "19", undated (Box 20, Folder 1662)
  - Duncan, Dollie (Tsuyohvsvi). Medical formula notebook, undated (Box 20, Folder 1663)
    Note on first page in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Duncan Book 3 Dec. 1964"
  - Medical formula notebook, undated (Box 20, Folder 1664)
    Note on cover in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Duncan Book II Dec. 1964" Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "document obtained from R. White guwoyi summer 1966"
  - Constitution of the Cherokee people and letter to Squirrel Sequichie, 1938 May 3 (Box 20, Folder 1665)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1666)
  - Medical formula, 1949 April (Box 20, Folder 1667)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1668)
  - Medical formula, before 1964 (Box 20, Folder 1669)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Tom Hawk coll. ob. July 1964"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1670)
  - Siquanida. Medical formula notebook, undated (Box 20, Folder 1671)
  - Recto: Letter from Jack Nichols of Congress, typed; Verso: Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1672)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1673)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1674)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1675)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1676)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1677)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1678)
  - Bible quotation, 1927 July 11 (Box 20, Folder 1679)
  - Medical formula fragment, undated (Box 20, Folder 1680)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Church meeting minutes in English, undated (Box 20, Folder 1681)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Grocery list in English, undated (Box 20, Folder 1682)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Reciept, undated (Box 20, Folder 1683)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1684)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1685)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1686)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1687)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1688)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1689)
  - Recto: Sycamore Tree Church note; Verso: Medical formula, 1946 November 10 (Box 20, Folder 1690)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Letter to Deer Stand Dave in English, 1943 September 22 (Box 20, Folder 1691)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Financial record, undated (Box 20, Folder 1692)
  - Medical formula and financial notebook, circa 1945 (Box 20, Folder 1693)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "tsegisini awigadoga collection [Jackson Standingdeer] found in spring of 1964 in half-gallon fruit jar in rotten black gum stump near Tenkiller Lake, close to Barber on tsegisini's place (obtained July 18, 1964)"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1694)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1695)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1696)
  - Letter or note, undated (Box 20, Folder 1697)
  - Recto: Letter in English and practice writing; Verso: Bible citations and medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1698)
  - Letter in English with bible citations and medical formula, 1944 April 21 (Box 20, Folder 1699)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1700)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1701)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Financial note, undated (Box 20, Folder 1702)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1703)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1704)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1705)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1706)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1707)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1708)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1709)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1710)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1711)
  - Medical formula and religious text collection, undated (Box 20, Folder 1712)
  - Medical formula collection, circa 1937 (Box 20, Folder 1713)
  - Medical formula collection, undated (Box 20, Folder 1714)
    Numbering for this collection aligns with that in folder 1713
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1715)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 20, Folder 1716)
  - Alan Kilpatrick annotated catalog of Uwedasat' manuscripts, undated (Box 20, Folder 1717)
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1896 (Box 20, Folder 1718)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' IV (1896 circa)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1905 (Box 20, Folder 1719)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' XIV (1905 circa) contains version of elohi gagusdv" Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "August I p9"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1886 (Box 20, Folder 1720)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Book II (1886 circa)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, undated (Box 20, Folder 1721)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' XII probably 19th century springfield wagon notebook 2 5/8 x 5 1/4"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, undated (Box 21, Folder 1722)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Formula Book LXXXI (formula on back cover)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1900 (Box 21, Folder 1723)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' XXXV (1900 circa) (with version of elohi gadusdvdi)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1905 (Box 21, Folder 1724)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' XXXIX 1905 circa"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1905 (Box 21, Folder 1725)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' LXIII 1905 circa"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1897 (Box 21, Folder 1726)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Formula Book LXV 3"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1897 (Box 21, Folder 1727)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' LXIV fragment 1897"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1902 (Box 21, Folder 1728)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Book III (1902 circa) contains "Christian" writing"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1905 (Box 21, Folder 1729)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' XIX (1905 circa)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1898 (Box 21, Folder 1730)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Sadega Svgi IV circa 1898"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1886 (Box 21, Folder 1731)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' LXVII (1886-1887)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1890 (Box 21, Folder 1732)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Formula Book XLVII 9 (circa 1890's)
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1900 (Box 21, Folder 1733)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' LXII (circa 1900)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1905 (Box 21, Folder 1734)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' XXXII (1905 circa)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1900 (Box 21, Folder 1735)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Formula Book XLIX 13 circa 1900"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, undated (Box 21, Folder 1736)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Formula Book LXXVII (probably 19th century)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1898 (Box 21, Folder 1737)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Formula Book LXVIII 13 (circa 1898)"
  - Medical formula notebook with envelope, circa 1889 (Box 21, Folder 1738)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Formula Book LXII (brown paper) probably by Jack Spaniard [?] Ap. 12 1889 [?] Aug. 30 1889"
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "21 Jack Spaniard 39 sheets c. 1889 Book LXXI"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 21, Folder 1739)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "39 Uwedasat' Formula Book LXXXIV 2pps (writing on 3 sides) (probably 19th century; stitches)"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 21, Folder 1740)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "35 Uwedasat' Formula Book LXXXIV (probably 19th century) 2pps - writing on 3 sides)"
  - Medical formula notebook in envelope, circa 1890 (Box 21, Folder 1741)
    Note on envelope in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Formula Book LXXXIII (stationary J.L. Rogers, stitched) 1890"
  - Jumper, Willie (Siquanida Dilidegi). Book of historical narratives, undated (Box 21, Folder 1742)
- Notebook #13: "Uwedasati No. 22, 19, 20 1940-1964"
  - Kilpatrick notebook cover #13, "Uwedasati No. 22, 19, 20 1940-1964", undated (Box 21, Folder 1743)
  - Journal or note, 1943 February (Box 21, Folder 1744)
  - Various notes; names, numbers, records in Cherokee and English, undated (Box 21, Folder 1745)
  - Letter or note, 1948 December 11 (Box 21, Folder 1746)
  - Wilkerson, George (Tsatsi Wilisini). Letter or note, undated (Box 21, Folder 1747)
  - Bliss, C.F. Letter to Jackson regarding case set for trial, 1947 September 10 (Box 21, Folder 1748)
  - Letter to author's grandfather, 1944 October 15 (Box 21, Folder 1749)
  - Letter to Mr. Wilson Doolet regarding the Standingdeer family, 1940 January 2 (Box 21, Folder 1750)
  - Letter to Rev. Smith Grass from Mulberry Tree Church and medical formula, 1943 March 15 (Box 21, Folder 1751)
  - List of names, titled "Geneva Glory", undated (Box 21, Folder 1752)
  - Bible citations and notes, 1946 March 31 (Box 21, Folder 1753)
  - Letter, 1947 September 14 (Box 21, Folder 1754)
  - Standingdeer, David (Dewi Awigadoga). Letter to Rev. Jackson Standingdeer, 1948 June 30 (Box 21, Folder 1755)
  - Uwedasat'. Letter or note, 1945 March 8 (Box 21, Folder 1756)
    Translated in Shadow, pp. 96-97
  - Financial record, 1942 March 3 (Box 21, Folder 1757)
  - Financial record, 1942 January 22 (Box 21, Folder 1758)
  - Financial record, 1943 April 5 (Box 21, Folder 1759)
  - Financial record, 1941 March 25 (Box 21, Folder 1759a)
  - Financial record, 1943 April 5 (Box 21, Folder 1760)
  - Sadega Egi. Journal or note, 1942 February 11 (Box 21, Folder 1761)
  - Ganawisosgi Nuwodvna. "Reminisce of World War I", 1964 March (Box 21, Folder 1762)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Ganawisosgi Doc" Translated in Shadow, pp. 107-108
  - Hogshooter, Susie B. Letter, undated (Box 21, Folder 1763)
  - Journal or note, undated (Box 21, Folder 1764)
  - Financial record, 1942 January 22 (Box 21, Folder 1765)
  - Financial record, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 1766)
  - Financial record, 1943 April 6 (Box 21, Folder 1767)
  - Financial record, 1943 September 15 (Box 21, Folder 1768)
  - Littledeer, Sam. Letter to Tom Proctor about fence post wood, 1961 February 3 (Box 22, Folder 1769)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Sam Littledeer Doc"
  - Petition to James W. Terrell and tax records with annotations in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, undated (Box 22, Folder 1770)
    Translated in Shadow, pp. 79
  - Recto: Note or Journal in English; Verso: Financial record, 1946 May 3 (Box 22, Folder 1771)
  - Financial record, undated (Box 22, Folder 1772)
  - Letter or note, signed "Atslagi (a Cherokee)", undated (Box 22, Folder 1773)
  - Belvin, B. Frank. Typed letter in English to "Fellow-worker" about Christian literature, 1947 May 15 (Box 22, Folder 1774)
  - Journal or note, 1953 March 15 (Box 22, Folder 1775)
  - Financial records, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 1776)
  - Journal or note, circa 1935 (Box 22, Folder 1777)
  - Otsikamiti. Note with list of names, 1941 September 19 (Box 22, Folder 1778)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Jennie Foster Coll."
  - Recto: Church or community record with list of names; Verso: Bible citations, 1955 May 30 (Box 22, Folder 1779)
    Translated in Shadow, pp. 102-103
  - Financial record, circa 1952 (Box 22, Folder 1780)
  - Church or community record, 1958 September (Box 22, Folder 1781)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwodige Giduwagi Doc. given June '63"
  - Personal note, 1945 June 22 (Box 22, Folder 1782)
  - Grocery list, undated (Box 22, Folder 1783)
  - Obituary, "Nvtsi Tsimi ayohvhi", 1946 July 5 (Box 22, Folder 1784)
  - Obituary, "ayohuhi Lawana uwetsi atsutsa Tsosuwa", 1945 April 12 (Box 22, Folder 1785)
  - Obituary, 1944 May 27 (Box 22, Folder 1786)
  - Obituary, 1945 February 10 (Box 22, Folder 1787)
  - Obituary, 1940 April 18 (Box 22, Folder 1788)
  - Obituary, 1940 April 20 (Box 22, Folder 1789)
  - Obituary, 1943 August 4 (Box 22, Folder 1790)
  - Personal note, 1954 May 12 (Box 22, Folder 1791)
  - Kanvtsuwa Nedi. Letter to Adie Chulis and envelope, 1943 June 3 (Box 22, Folder 1792)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Ada Bunch Coll. II [?] 25, 1963" Translated in Shadow, pp. 95
  - List of names, undated (Box 22, Folder 1793)
  - Letter to Ada Chulis and envelope, 1943 May 12 (Box 22, Folder 1794)
  - Letter to Ada Chulis and envelope, 1943 May 28 (Box 22, Folder 1795)
  - List of 144 names, undated (Box 22, Folder 1796)
  - List of names, undated (Box 22, Folder 1797)
  - Letter or note, titled "itsitsalagi itsehvi", undated (Box 22, Folder 1798)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Salem Church Coll. acquired from Johanna Feather [?] 1963"
  - Starr, C.J. Letter to Dollie Duncan on Oklahoma State Penitentiary stationary, 1951 March 25 (Box 22, Folder 1799)
  - Letter or note, 1936 June 26 (Box 22, Folder 1800)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Duncan Coll. 3 Dec. 1964"
  - Community record, list of names and tallies, 1940 August 5 (Box 22, Folder 1801)
  - Community record, "dunatlosvgi anigiduwa ugvwalvno", 1940 (Box 22, Folder 1802)
  - Geyudiga. Journal entries, undated (Box 22, Folder 1803)
  - Journal or note, 1947 December 25 (Box 22, Folder 1804)
  - Church record, undated (Box 22, Folder 1805)
  - Bible study, "Translated by Robt. Chumestudy", 1935 (Box 22, Folder 1806)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Document obtained from Mary [?] guwoi [?], summer 1966"
  - Our Daily Bread booklet 1963 with Cherokee note on back, 1964 March 18 (Box 22, Folder 1807)
  - Geyudiga Advga. Letter, 1944 September 6 (Box 22, Folder 1808)
  - Nenisi Tsalo (Armeecher, Nancy). Letter, 1957 March 11 (Box 22, Folder 1809)
  - Sycamore Church notes, 1943 February 14 (Box 22, Folder 1810)
  - Dewisi Awigadoga (Standingeer, Davis). Letter to John Standingdeer, 1947 March 27 (Box 22, Folder 1811)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Bill Bolin Coll. (obtained Sept. 1963)"
  - Letter, undated (Box 22, Folder 1812)
  - Turtle, Rachel. Letter, 1961 March 5 (Box 22, Folder 1813)
  - Church or community note, undated (Box 22, Folder 1814)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Tom Hawk Coll. ob. July 1964"
  - Personal note, "halsdayvhvga", undated (Box 22, Folder 1815)
  - Peoples Bank check to Mrs Lillian Watt, undated (Box 22, Folder 1816)
  - Journal or note, August 1950 (Box 22, Folder 1817)
  - Peoples Bank checks, undated (Box 22, Folder 1818)
  - Egi Iladv. Letter, 1947 September 7 (Box 22, Folder 1819)
  - Financial record and list of names, 1945 September 16 (Box 22, Folder 1820)
  - List of names, undated (Box 22, Folder 1821)
  - Tsali Wadi (Watt, Charlie). Journal or note, undated (Box 22, Folder 1822)
  - Washington, George. Letter to Jack Kilpatrick, 1965 January 25 (Box 22, Folder 1823)
  - Washington, George. Letter to Jack Kilpatrick and envelope, 1963 September 5 (Box 22, Folder 1824)
  - Washington, George. Letter to Jack Kilpatrick, 1965 October 19 (Box 22, Folder 1825)
  - Washington, George. Letter to Jack Kilpatrick in Cherokee and English and envelope, 1963 August 26 (Box 22, Folder 1826)
  - Recto: Historical narrative; Verso: Description of text in English, undated (Box 22, Folder 1827)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Jim Laughead Doc. copied by Siquanida (Sept. 1963)"
  - US Registration Certificate of Joe Waterdown, 1917 June 5 (Box 22, Folder 1828)